[
  {
    "question": "Which language is commonly used for back-end development?",
    "options": [
      ".Net",
      "Java",
      "Python",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which languages are commonly used for front-end development?",
    "options": [
      "HTML",
      "CSS",
      "JavaScript",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a correct statement?",
    "options": [
      "HTML is used to create web pages",
      "CSS is used to make styles",
      "JavaScript is used to write the logic",
      "Java, .NET, Python are used for front-end development"
    ],
    "answer": "Java, .NET, Python are used for front-end development"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Home Tool Markup Language",
      "Hyperlinking Text Management Language",
      "HyperText Markup Language",
      "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language"
    ],
    "answer": "HyperText Markup Language"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a markup language?",
    "options": [
      "A database language",
      "A language that uses tags to define the structure of content",
      "A programming language to perform calculations",
      "A styling language for web pages"
    ],
    "answer": "A language that uses tags to define the structure of content"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term “HyperText” in HTML mean?",
    "options": [
      "Text with audio",
      "Text with clickable links",
      "Text with styles",
      "Text with images"
    ],
    "answer": "Text with clickable links"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does metadata refer to in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "CSS file linking",
      "JavaScript file linking",
      "Font & icons information",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the present version of HTML?",
    "options": [
      "HTML-3",
      "HTML-2",
      "HTML-4",
      "HTML-5"
    ],
    "answer": "HTML-5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created HTML?",
    "options": [
      "Dennis Ritchie",
      "Charles Babbage",
      "James Gosling",
      "Tim Berners-Lee"
    ],
    "answer": "Tim Berners-Lee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can a web page contain?",
    "options": [
      "Images and hyperlinks",
      "Headings and paragraphs",
      "Forms like login and register",
      "Audio and video files",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who maintains HTML standards?",
    "options": [
      "ISO (International Organization for Standardization)",
      "ECMA (European Computer Manufacturers Association)",
      "IEEE (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers)",
      "W3C (World Wide Web Consortium)"
    ],
    "answer": "W3C (World Wide Web Consortium)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following execute HTML code?",
    "options": [
      "Browsers",
      "Compilers",
      "JVM",
      "Runtime Environment"
    ],
    "answer": "Browsers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tag symbol used in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "Opening: < >  Closing: </>",
      "Opening: ( )  Closing: {}",
      "Closing: < >  Opening: </>",
      "Closing: ()   Opening: (/)"
    ],
    "answer": "Opening: < >  Closing: </>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are examples of HTML Editors?",
    "options": [
      "Notepad",
      "Editplus",
      "Notepad++",
      "SublimeText",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are examples of IDEs used for web development?",
    "options": [
      "WebStorm",
      "Dreamweaver",
      "Visual Studio Code",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which section of the HTML document contains the visible content?",
    "options": [
      "<html>",
      "<body>",
      "<head>",
      "<!DOCTYPE>"
    ],
    "answer": "<body>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which section of the HTML document contains the meta data information?",
    "options": [
      "<html>",
      "<body>",
      "<head>",
      "<!DOCTYPE>"
    ],
    "answer": "<head>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag defines the HTML version of the document?",
    "options": [
      "<html>",
      "<head>",
      "<body>",
      "<!DOCTYPE>"
    ],
    "answer": "<!DOCTYPE>"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the root element of the document?",
    "options": [
      "<html>",
      "<head>",
      "<body>",
      "<!DOCTYPE>"
    ],
    "answer": "<html>"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tag used for title of web page?",
    "options": [
      "<h1>",
      "<head>",
      "<title>",
      "<caption>"
    ],
    "answer": "<title>"
  }
]